Guide to the William Blathwayt Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1646-1796; Series I; 4.0' (10 boxes)
  - Friesen, Julius Heinrich, Graf von
    - 32 ALS (in French) to William Blathwayt, The Hague, Frankfurt, Augsburg, Vienna, Camp at Bruchsal, 1696/7 Jan 2/12- (Box 3, Folder 67)
      - English and Dutch forces in the Upper Rhine about his conferences with the Pensioner, Stepney, the Emperor, Lexington, and others, subsidies for the troops, and preparations for battle against the French. Accompanied by an account of Bills of Exchange drawn by Comte de Frise (Friesen) on 1697 May 13/23. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697. 3. Holy Roman Empire. Sovereigns, etc., 1658-1705 (Leopold I). 4. Stepney, George, 1663-1707. 5. Lexington, Robert Sutton, 2nd Baron, 1661-1723.
    - 4 ALS (in French) to Lord Albemarle, The Hague, Vienna, Frankfurt, 1697 Feb 22- (Box 3, Folder 68)
      - Writing as commander-in-chief of the, Jun 16
      - forces in the Upper Rhine to one of his generals about diplomatic preparations to the summer campaign. 1. Albemarle, Arnold Joost van Keppel, 1st Earl of, 1669-1718. 2. Great Britain. Army. 3. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.
    - Letter (copy, in French) to William Blathwayt, 1697 Mar 30
      Concerning allied troops on the Rhine. 1. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.
    - 2 letters (copies) to Baron Goerz, Frankfurt, 1697 Jun 11, 15
      Concerning orders for troops on the Rhine; accompanied by Goerz's reply to Frise's letter of 11 June. Goerz was a Minister to the Landgrave of of Hesse-Cassel. 1. Goerz, Baron de. 2. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.
    - 34 ALS and 1 LS (in French) to William Blathwayt, Frankfurt, Augsburg, and various military camps, 1697 Jul 4- (Box 3, Folder 69)
      - Dispatches about summer military, Dec 31
      - operations, the cessation of hostilities, the conclusion of peace, and the disposition of troops. 1. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697. 2. Ryswick, Peace of, 1697. 3. Great Britain. Army.
    - 3 ALS to William Blathwayt, The Hague and Frankfurt, 1698 Jun 17- (Box 3, Folder 70)
      - Concerning orders for troops and, Sep 14/24
      - subsidies for allies. 1. Great Britain. Army.
    - 3 ALS (in French) to William Blathwayt, Rastatt and Frankfurt, 1701/2 Jan 30-
      - Concerning troops on the Rhine., 1702 May 9
      - 1. Spanish Succession, War of the, 1701-1714.
    - 3 ALS (in French) to Lord Lexington, Rastatt, 1702 Mar 31-
      - Responding to news of the king's, Apr 21
      - death and discussing the role of the army under the new monarch. 1. Lexington, Robert Sutton, 2nd Baron, 1661-1723. 2. Great Britain. Army.
  - Friesen, Grafin von
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, The Hague, 1697 Mar 2/12
      Acknowledging arrangements for her trip to Frankfurt to join her husband. 1. Friesen, Julius Heinrich, Count von.
  - Galway, Lord
    See: Ruvigny and Raineval, Henri de Massue de Ruvigny, 2nd Marquis of, 1648-1720
  - Geneva
    - "Memorial about Geneva": contemporary ms. copy, in French, [ca. 1698] (Box 3, Folder 71)
      Concerning relationship with Savoy. 1. Savoy--Foreign relations--Geneva.
  - Gibson, John, Sir, 1637-1717
    - 2 ALS to William Blathwayt, Portsmouth, [1702?} (Box 3, Folder 72)
      Asking for a dispensation from service for his son Francis Gibson to continue his studies in mathematics at Balliol, and recommending men to take up vacant positions as officers in his company. 1. Gibson, Francis, b. 1684?
    - 15 ALS to William Blathwayt, Portsmouth, 1702/3 Jan 1-31
      Acknowledging orders and reporting on movement of troops, quartering of soldiers, recruiting, musters, the serious lack of officers, and the embarking of Col. Colenbine's and Col. Holt's regiments to join Rear Admiral Leake. The letter of Jan 14 contains a copy of an undated letter of Leake to Gibson and the letter of Jan 19 includes an abstract of the four companies of Col. Holt's regiment. 1. Erle, Thomas, 1650?-1720. 2. Great Britain. Army. 3. Great Britain. Navy. 4. Colenbine, Ventris. 5. Holt, Henry, d. 1714? I. Leake, John, Sir, 1656-1720.
    - 10 ALS to William Blathwayt, Portsmouth, 1702/3 Feb 2-14 (Box 3, Folder 73)
      Acknowledging orders and reporting on the embarking of Colenbine's regiment, the progress of transport ships and the Portugal fleet, musters, and the capture of several Frenchman. 1. Erle, Thomas, 1650?-1720. 2. Leake, John, Sir, 1652-1720. 3. Colenbine, Ventris. 4. Great Britain. Army. 5. Great Britain. Navy.
    - 6 ALS to William Blathwayt, Portsmouth, 1702 May 15-
      - Writing as lieutenant governor of, Dec 30
      - Portsmouth with reports on French prisoners and an attempted escape, movement of troops through Portsmouth, musters, and quartering of soldiers. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Portsmouth, England.
  - Godolphin, Sidney Godolphin, 1st Earl of, 1645-1712
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, [London], 1692 May 13 (Box 4, Folder 74)
      Concerns the dispatching of bills from Whitehall for use of William III's court in Flanders.
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], [London], 1693 May 5
      Discussing the extreme difficulty of funding the campaigns of the army in what he calls "the most unaccountable proceeding that I have ever heard of." 1. Great Britain. Army.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, [London], 1693 Aug 4
      Responding to news of the army; "...you have gain'd a great deale of honour & reputation, tho you have not gain'd the battell..."
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, [London], 1693 Sep 12
      Acknowledging receipt of Blathwayt's remarks upon proposals for a tax in the plantations and reporting on deliberations at the Treasury concerning a Blathwayt petition. 1. Great Britain. Board of Trade. 2. Great Britain. Treasury.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, [London], 1694 Apr 29 (Box 4, Folder 74)
      Concerning shipment of provisions and Blathwayt's salary. 1. Great Britain. Commissioners of Transport.
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], [London], 1695 May 31
      Concerning the terms under which the Bank of England will underwrite "the remises for a yeare." 1. Bank of England. 2. Godfrey, Michael, d. 1695.
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], [London], 1695 Jun 3
      About raising £3000 to cover Lord Bellamont's debts so that might take up his appointment as governor of New England. 1. Bellamont, Richard Coote, 1st Earl of, 1636-1701
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, [London], 1695 Jun 28
      Arguing against the proposal for an encampment at Hounslow Heath which George Clarke had presented to the Treasury on behalf of William III. 1. Clarke, George, 1661-1736. 2. Great Britain. Army. 3. Great Britain. Treasury.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, [London], 1695 Jul 26
      Wishes to comply with William III's orders concerning Sir Samuel Barnardiston, but he does not yet know what they are. 1. Barnardiston, Samuel, Sir, 1620-1707.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, [London], 1695 Aug 15 (Box 4, Folder 74)
      Asking Blathwayt to help obtain a pass for the singer John Abell to return to England from Germany, "for the divertisements of the Town." 1. Abell, John, 1660?-1716?
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], [London], 1695 Aug 23
      Discusses the importance of the Siege of Namur to England and recommends that allies be persuaded to take subsidies in commodities rather than coin. 1. Godfrey, Michael, d. 1695. 2. Bank of England. 3. Great Britain. Army.
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], [London], 1695 Sep 10
      Provisions for the army; loss of East India ships; pass for John Abell. 1. Abell, John, 1660?-1716? 2. Great Britain. Army. 3. Bank of England. 4. East India Company (English).
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, [London], 1695 Sep 24
      Necessity of King being in England before writs go out for a new parliament, and troubles caused by loss of East India ships. 1. Great Britain. Parliament, 1695. House of Commons. 2. East India Company (English).
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], [London], [1696] May 29
      Enclosing a letter for the King.
    - Letter (copy) to Lord Halifax, Treasury Chambers, 1703 Apr 14
      Warrant for payment of £125 to Edward Southwell as his half year salary as Clerk of the Council. 1. Halifax, Charles Montagu, 1st Earl of, 1661-1715. 2. Southwell, Edward, 1671-1730.
  - Goës, Robert
    - LS (in Dutch) to William III, Copenhagen, 1701 Aug 16
      Concerning the defensive alliance of 1701 between Denmark, England, and the Netherlands. Goës was the Dutch envoy in Copenhagen. 1. William III, King of Great Britain, 1650-1702. 2. Great Britain. Treaties, etc., 1694-1702 (William III). 3. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Denmark. 4. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Netherlands. 5. Netherlands--Foreign relations--Denmark.
  - Great Britain. Army
    - Calculation of carriage costs for a company and a regiment in Ireland, [ca. 1700] (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Memorandum about the contract for bread, 1703
    - Documents relating to allied troops during the war of the Grand Alliance, 1693-95
      Contents include a list of additional troops raised by the Dutch, 1693; calculations of extra charges for the army in 1693 and 1694; subsidies for allies, 1694; cost of the land forces in 1694; accounts of the numerical strength of armies of the various allies; lists of forces in the Low Countries and in the Rhine area. 1. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689- 1697.
    - Memorandum (in Dutch) of the ammunition at Exeter., [ca. 1689]
  - Great Britain. Board of Trade
    - "Clauses in the Commission for Trade": contemporary ms. copy, [ca. 1696] (Box 4, Folder 76)
      Two clauses referring to membership and quorums.
  - Great Britain. Catholics
    - Proposals for protecting the Catholic interest: anon. ms., 1686 Nov 9
      Arguing that James II's real enemies are the Anglicans and that he should join with the Prince and Princess of Orange. 1. Church of England--History. 2. Dissenters. 3. James II. King of Great Britain, 1633-1701.
  - Great Britain. Commissioners for Transport
    - 2 LS to [William Blathwayt], Transport Office, 1698 May 11, 14 (Box 4, Folder 77)
      Asking for directions for selling excess casks in Transport Office; signed by Samuel Atkinson & John Henley. Accompanied by an estimate of the value of the casks. 1. Great Britain. Army. I. Atkinson, Samuel. II. Henley, John.
    - "An Account of ships now in the Port of Waterford", 1703/4 Jan 27
      List of ships carrying wool to England, with notes on the number of soldiers on each one. 1. Great Britain. Navy.
    - Letter (copy) to John Tucker, n.p., 1705 Dec 13
      Concerning Transport ships from Barcelona or Lisbon putting in at British ports; signed by Samuel Atkinson, Nicholas Roope, and T. Colby. 1. Tucker, John. I. Atkinson, Samuel. II. Roope, Nicholas. III. Colby, T.
    - LS to [William Blathwayt], Transport Office, 1698 Sep 9
      Responding to a direction to discharge one of their agents; signed by Samuel Atkinson, Anthony Duncombe, & Thomas Hopkins. I. Atkinson, Samuel. II. Duncombe, Anthony. III. Hopkins, Thomas.
  - Great Britain. Commissioners for Victualling
    - "Calculation of the Victualling for the year 1693": contemporary ms. copy, 1693 Jul 1 (Box 4, Folder 78)
      Costs at the ports and for the fleet. 1. Great Britain. Navy.
  - Great Britain. Customs Establishment
    - "Old Farmers of the Customs Report": contemporary ms. copy, [ca. 1663]
      Documenting the claims of Sir John Wolstenholme, Sir Paul Pindar, and Sir John Jacob against the Customs account in the reign of Charles I. 1. Wolstenholme, John, 1st bart., 1596-1670. 2. Pindar, Paul, 1st bart., d. 1693? 3. Jacob, John, 1st bart., 1598?-1666.
  - Great Britain. French Commissioners
    - "Memoire touchant les françois Refugiez en Suisse pour la Religion": contemporary ms. copy, [1690?]
      Endorsed by Blathwayt 1. Huguenots--Switzerland.
  - Great Britain. Lords Justices
    - "List of Papers delivered in to the Councill by my Lord Berkeley & Mr. Meesters relating to the Action at Dunkirk [1695 Aug 1]," London, 1695 Aug [6] (Box 4, Folder 79)
      Concerns the Council meeting of 6 August; cf. C.S.P.D., 1695 p. 37. The papers of Col. Richards, Capt. Stewart, and Capt. Jennings are summarized. 1. Berkeley, Charles Berkeley, 2nd Earl of, 1649-1710. 2. Meisters, William. 3. Richards, Jacob, 1660?-1701. 4. Benbow, John, 1653-1702. 5. Jennings, John, 1664- 1743. 6. Great Britain. Navy.
  - Great Britain. Navy
    - "A List of ships...ordered to be kept in readiness to proceed to the Streights": contemporary ms. copy, [1695 Aug 30] (Box 4, Folder 80)
      The orders had been given by the Lords Justices; the list was sent to Blathwayt. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices.
    - "Advices concerning the Mediterranean Fleet": contemporary ms. copy, 1693 Jul 3
      Extracts from two anonymous newsletters.
    - "List of the Ships in Cadiz and St. Lucar": contemporary ms. copy, [ca. 1695] Jun 28-
      - Including a list of allied ships., 30
      - 1. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.
    - "An Account of the Victualling of the Fleet": contemporary ms. copy, 1693 Jun 30
      - Accompanied by a copy of the same list of provisions. 1. Great Britain. Commissioners for Victualling.
        See: Oversize, Box 12, folder 237
  - Great Britain. Parliament
    - Declaration of Lords and Commons: anon. ms., [1688/9 Feb 12] (Box 4, Folder 81)
      Enumerates reasons why the throne is vacant, lists rights of the English people, and offers the throne to William and Mary. Printed with minor word differences as The Declaration of The Lords Spiritual and temporal, and Commons, 1689, Wing E1489. 1. Great Britain. Sovereigns, etc., 1689-1694 (William and Mary).
    - Report on the free conference with the Lords on the Bill for reversing two judgments against Titus Oates: anon. ms. (copy), [1689 Aug 2]
      Report by Solicitor General Somers on the conference between the two Houses held 29 July 1689 about Titus Oates. Printed with minor word changes in C. J. K., p. 247-51 and Cobbett, Parl. Hist. V, p. 386-96. 1. Oates, Titus, 1648-1705. 2. Great Britain. Parliament, 1684, House of Commons. I. Somers, John Somers, Baron, 1651-1716.
  - Great Britain. Privy Council
    - "The order of Councill declaring his Majesties satisfaction in the deportmt. of Sr. R. Southwell concerning the Busines of the Earl of Anglesey," Whitehall, 1669 Oct 13 (Box 4, Folder 82)
      Copy from the Privy Council register, attested by Richard Browne. 1. Southwell, Robert, Sir, 1635-1702. 2. Anglesey, Arthur Annerley, 1st Earl of, 1614-1686. I. Browne, Richard, bart., 1605?-1683.
  - Great Britain. Sovereigns, etc., 1625-1649 (Charles I)
    - "Proclamation for the fair": contemporary ms., [ca. 1646] (Box 4, Folder 83)
      Draft proclamations, oaths for officials, and calculations of costs for a Lenten fair. 1. Great Britain--Social life and customs--17th century.
  - Great Britain. Sovereigns, etc., 1685-1688 (James II)
    - Warrant for creating the Ecclesiastical Commission: contemporary ms. copy, [1688]
      1. Great Britain. Ecclesiastical Commission, 1686-1688.
    - Instructions for Lord Lieutenants: contemporary ms. copy, [1687 Oct]
      Questions to ask of all Deputy Lieutenants and prospective M.P.'s about their support for James II's religious policies. Cf. C.S.P.D., 1687-89, 440- 1. Great Britain. Parliament, 1687.
  - Great Britain. Sovereigns, etc., 1689-1694 (William and Mary)
    - Notes for a Speech: anon. ms., [ca. 1689] (Box 4, Folder 84)
      Concerning the calling of Parliament in Scotland. 1. Scotland. Parliament, 1689-1690.
    - "Draught of a Declaration ag[ains]t Lodging of Soldiers in private houses.", Court of St. James, 1688/9 Jan 5
      - Issued while Prince of Orange. 1. Great Britain. Army.
        See: Oversize, Box 12, folder 238
    - Letter received from Madrid, (in French), Madrid, 1693 Aug 6
      Reporting a French naval attack against Spain. 1. France--Foreign relations--Spain.
    - Credentials for Stepney's mission in Saxony: contemporary ms. copy, Whitehall, 1693 Sep 22
      1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Saxony. 2. Stepney, George, 1663-1707.
  - Great Britain. Sovereigns, etc. 1694-1702 (William III)
    - 4 letters, (copies, in Latin) to heads of German states. Kensington, 1687 Mar 25 (Box 4, Folder 85)
      Addressed to the Count Palatine, Elector Palatine, Elector of Saxony, and Markgraf of Baden. 1. Friedrich August I, der Starke, Elector of Saxony and King of Poland, 1670-1733. 2. Johann Wilhelm, Elector Palatine, 1658-1716. 3. Ludwig Wilhelm, Markgraf von Baden-Baden, 1655-1707.
    - "Instructions for the Earl of Marlborough": contemporary ms. copy, Hampton Court, 1701 Jun 26
      Instructions for Marlborough to treat and conclude an alliance with the Emperor, the States General, and "such other Princes as are willing to enter into the same." Printed in W. S. Churchill's Marlborough, vol. I, App. III, p. 573-74. 1. Marlborough, John Churchill, 1st Duke of, 1650-1722. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Holy Roman Empire. 3. Great Britain-- Foreign relations--Netherlands.
    - "The Earl of Marlborough's Instructions": contemporary ms. copy, Hampton Court, 1701 Jun 26
      Instructions for Marlborough to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary at the Hague for negotiations for the peace of Europe. Printed in W. S. Churchill's Marlborough, vol. I, app. III, p. 571-73. 1. Marlborough, John Churchill, 1st Duke of, 1650-1702. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Netherlands.
    - Draft instructions for the Earl of Marlborough, Loo, 1701 Sep 10, 12
      Draft instructions in William Blathwayt's hand for treating with the States General, Prussia, and Sweden. 1. Marlborough, John Churchill, 1st Duke of, 1650-1722. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Netherlands. 3. Great Britain-- Foreign relations--Prussia. 4. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Sweden.
    - "The Earl of Marlborough's Credentials": contemporary ms. copy in French, The Hague, 1701 Jul 4
      Marlborough's credentials for treating with the various sovereigns of Europe. 1. Marlborough, John Churchill, 1st Duke of, 1650-1722.
  - Great Britain. Treasury
    - "Scheme concerning the Expence & Funds of the Civil List": anon. ms., 1713/14 Feb 4 (Box 4, Folder 86)
      List of expences in various categories for the previous year, with observations and proposals for reform. An additional note is apparently in the hand of Sir Thomas Hanmer. 1. Civil List--Great Britain. 2. Great Britain--Royal Household. I. Hanmer, Thomas, 4th bart., 1677- 1746.
      See: Oversize, Box 12, folder 239
    - Treasury warrant, fragment, to William Blathwayt, Treasury Chambers, 1716 Aug 7
      Referring to salaries and allowances payable in Virginia. 1. Virginia--History--Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775.
  - Great Britain. Treaties, etc., 1694-1702 (William III)
    - "Project of Agreement between Sweden, England, & Holland": contemporary ms. copy in Dutch, [ca. 1696] (Box 4, Folder 87)
      1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Sweden. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Netherlands.
    - "List of Treaties, and the Treaties wanting": contemporary ms. copy, [ca. 1703]
      Apparently a catalogue of treaties with German and Scandinavian states.
  - Greenefield, Jonathan
    - "An Account of ye Sufferings of Mr. Greenfield of Cardiff in France": anon. ms. (Box 4, Folder 88)
      The story of his trial and imprisonment in France for attempting to transport French protestants to Britain. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- France.
  - Greg, Hugh, d. 1702
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Copenhagen, 1696 Aug 4
      Writing as English chargé d'affaires with news.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Copenhagen, 1698 Jul 23/
      - "Sir. Since my last I have met with a, Aug 2
      - person that has some knowledge of the Treaty ..."
  - Guy, Henry, 1631-1710
    - 32(?) LS to William Blathwayt, Treasury Chambers, 1691 Jun 26- (Box 4, Folder 89-90)
      - Writing as Secretary to the Lords of, 1691/2 Feb 26
      - the Treasury to Blathwayt for him to prepare warrants for Army payments by Charles Fox, Thomas Coningsby, Earl of Ranelagh, or Jacob VanderEsch. The retained copies of these letters were described in Calendar of Treasury Books, IX, pt. III & IV. I. Great Britain. Treasury. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Ranelagh, Richard Jones, 1st Earl of, 1636?-1712. 3. Fox, Charles, d. 1713. 4. Coningsby, Thomas Coningsby, Earl, 1656?-1729. 5. VanderEsch, Jacob.
  - Gwyn, Francis, 1648?-1734
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt?], Whitehall, 1688 Oct 18 (Box 4, Folder 91)
      Reporting the latest news on the eve of the Glorious Revolution: the fleet should leave Holland tommorrow and Edward Russel has joined the Prince. 1. William III, King of Great Britain, 1650-1702. 2. Orford, Edward Russel, Earl of, 1653-1727.
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt?], London, 1690 Jun 6
      Recommending Nicholas Fenn for Ferguson's place as House Keeper of the Excise office. 1. Fenn, Nicholas. 2. Ferguson, Robert, d. 1714.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, n.p., 1702 Apr 18
      Conveying the wish of Rochester that Blathwayt expedite transport of arms to Ireland. 1. Rochester, Laurence Hyde, 1st Earl of, 1641-1711. 2. Great Britain. Army.
  - Haggerston, Thomas, Sir, d. 1710?
    - 6 ALS to William Blathwayt, Berwick, 1688 May 30- (Box 4, Folder 92)
      - Writing as governor of Berwick, Sep 16
      - Castle with reports on the town, the arrest of three deserters, the payment of troops with English money, and the loyalty of his officers to James II. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Berwick-on-Tweed, England.
  - Hales, John, Colonel
    - 3 ALS to William Blathwayt, Canterbury, 1688 Aug 27-
      - Reporting the political situation in, Sep 9
      - Canterbury, especially pressures from the Citizens against the Mayor and Recorder for standing for Parliament by James II's command. 1. Great Britain. Parliament-- Elections. 2. Canterbury, England.
  - Hamburg. Senate
    - Letter (in High Dutch(?)) to the Emperor, [Hamburg], 1691 Sep 15 (Box 4, Folder 93)
      Accompanied by a translation in Latin. 1. Leopold I. Emperor of Germany, 1640-1705.
  - Handasyd, Thomas
    - 3 ALS to William Blathwayt, Jamaica, 1702 Jul 2- (Box 4, Folder 94)
      - Reports on the "sickly" state of the, Sep 25
      - island and the need for more troops and officers. Asks whether the island is an Irish or an English establishment. Third letter acknowledges the arrival of the regiment. 1. Jamaica--History.
  - Hanover (Electorate)
    - "Sentence against the Molles, etc. at Hanover": contemporary ms. copy in German, 1692 Jul 8
      Endorsed by Sir Paul Rycaut. 1. Rycaut, Paul, Sir, 1628-1700.
  - Hawker, Henry
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], London, 1702 Oct 1
      About the difficulties caused by shortage of hay and high prices in quartering troops around Hull. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Hedges, Charles, Sir, d. 1714
    - LS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1701 Jul 4 (Box 4, Folder 95)
      Sending a warrant for allowance to Richard Warre as secretary to Marlborough. 1. Warre, Richard.
    - LS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1701 Jul 8
      Relating request by M. Leyoncrona, the Swedish envoy, for more cloth and a request by William Aldersey to be made English agent in Hamburg. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Sweden. 2. Aldersey, William.
    - LS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1701 Jul 15
      Concerning the alleged discovery of a pretended plot by one William Bromefield. 1. Bromefield, William.
    - LS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1701 Jul 18
      Swedish diplomatic intentions; forming a quorum among aldermen of London. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Sweden. 2. London Corporation. Court of Common Council.
    - LS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1701 Jul 22 (Box 4, Folder 95)